Southwest Folklore Center Magdalena de Kino painted glass collection, 1965- (bulk 1976- )
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Southwest Folklore Center Magdalena de Kino painted glass collection, 1965- (bulk 1976- )
SWF 003
University of Arizona. Southwest Folklore Center
10 linear feet
The collection consists of examples of reverse painting on glass objects, usually with tin borders, decorative trim or frames. The painted glass collection includes crosses; pieces intended for wall hanging; boxes and examples of unfinished pieces; and pieces from cultural traditions outside the Magdalena de Kino, Mexico, area. The pieces in this collection represent the work of itinerant artisans known as pajareros, or "birdcatchers," from Magdalena de Kino, Mexico.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Organization
This collection is organized into six series:
I. Crosses, 1979-
II. Rectangular Pieces, 1976-
III. Boxes, 1980-
IV. Unfinished Works, Templates, and Comparison Pieces
Photographs, 1965-
V. Pieces From Other Arizona/Sonora Borderland Locations 1998-1999
Scope and Content Note
Specimens of reverse painting on glass backed with tinfoil and either cardboard or tin. The majority of the specimens are crosses, rectangular pieces or boxes. Some pieces incorporate a commercially printed illustration of a saint into the design. All pieces have been collected in Magdalena de Kino, Sonora, Mexico, during the city's annual festival honoring its patron saint, San Francisco. Also included in the collection are unpainted glass boxes containing statuettes of San Francisco, a number of unfinished pieces, a hand-drawn template, and several comparison pieces from other cultural traditions. The collection also includes photographs of artisans and Magdalena de Kino festival scenes.
The collection consists of examples of reverse painting on glass objects, usually with tin borders, decorative trim or frames. The collection includes crosses; pieces intended for wall hanging; boxes and examples of unfinished pieces; and pieces from cultural traditions outside the Magdalena de Kino, Mexico, area. The pieces in this collection represent the work of itinerant artisans known as pajareros, or "birdcatchers," from Magdalena de Kino, Mexico, who make and sell them at the annual festival of San Francisco in Magdalena de Kino, Mexico. The major forms of these pieces are decorative crosses, rectangular pieces intended for wall hanging, and decorative boxes. The rectangular pieces usually include a clear area in the glass for the inclusion of an illustration, either supplied by the artist, or for the purchaser to customize. The collection also includes clear glass boxes with tin frames containing the likeness of San Francisco, the patron saint of Magdalena de Kino. The collection includes photographs of painted glass artisans, scenes from the festival of San Francisco, and scenery from the surrounding Sonoran countryside.
Artists represented in the collection include Francisco, Gregoria and Guadelupe Guttierez; Anastacio, Eduardo, Jesús, Matilde and Martín León; Álvaro and Catalina Moreno; Olga Ruiz; and members of the Francisco Silva family. The collection does not necessarily represent a complete sample of all styles of art for sale in any given year. Attempts have been made, however, to see that all artists are represented in the pieces collected each year. Each piece in the collection is identified by name, year, and sequence number as follows: Surname, First Name: Year - Sequence Number. Where the date or artist are unknown, this is indicated in the appropriate portion of the identifier.
Griffith, James S.; Guttierez, Francisco; Guttierez, Gregoria; Guttierez, Guadelupe; León, Anastacio; León, Eduardo; León, Jesús; León, Matilde; León, Martín; Moreno, Álvaro; Martín López, María del Pilar; Ruiz, Olga; University of Arizona. Southwest Folklore Center; Art, Mexican -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Glass underpainting -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Folk art -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Christian art and symbolism -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Reverse painting on glass -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Artifacts -- Mexico -- Magdalena de Kino; Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Crosses, 1979-
  Most crosses include decorative tin finials (pieces placed on the four ends of the crosses). The dates on all crosses are suffixed by the letter "c" to denote them as such. All are in good condition unless otherwise noted.
  - Text to accompany a painted glass exhibit in the University of Arizona Library Special Collections. October 1 - November 25, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Leon family: 1997c-1. Abstract pattern (pseudo-combed), no image, trapezoidal base, no finials, decorative tin work. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - León, Anastacio: 1994c-1. Abstract pattern, image of the Sacred Heart, trapezoidal base, no finials. Chipped paint. 1994 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995c-1. Abstract pattern, no image, stepped base, tin finials. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995c-2. Geometric pattern, no image, stepped base, tin finials. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996c-1. Abstract pattern, no image, trapezoidal base, tin finials. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - León, Jesús: 1979c-1. Floral pattern, images of San José and San Francisco, trapezoidal base, no finials. Fair condition. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - León, Jesús: 1981c-1. Floral pattern, images of Jesus and the Virgin of Guadalupe, trapezoidal base, no finials. Fair condition. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - León, Jesús: 1984c-1. Abstract pattern, images of the vision of the Virgin of Guadalupe and San Francisco, trapezoidal base, no finials. Broken glass. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - León, Jesús: 1988c-1. Abstract pattern, images of the Santo Niño de Atocha and San Martín Caballero, trapezoidal base, no finials. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - León, Jesús: 1990c-1. Abstract pattern, images of Jesus and Saint Luke, trapezoidal base, no finials. Broken weld. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - León, Matilde: 1996c-1. Abstract pattern, no image, trapezoidal base, no finials, decorative tin work. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - León, Matilde: 1996c-2. Geometric pattern, no image, trapezoidal base, no finials, decorative tin work. 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1995c-1. Floral pattern, image of the Holy Trinity, no base, no finials. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Series II: Rectangular Pieces, 1976-
  These pieces usually include a rectangular opening in the glass in which a commercially printed illustration has been placed. Some pieces include a blank opening for completion by the purchaser. All pieces labeled "León Family" were sold at the León family booth, however the specific artist within the family is unknown. All of Olga Ruiz's pieces have cardboard backings which are held on by handmade clips of tin. Item descriptions include a description of the shape of the opening. All are in good condition unless otherwise noted.
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1979-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. Loose clips and chipped glass. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1979-2. Floral pattern, no image: 2 hearts. Scratched glass. 1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1980-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. Scratched paint and chipped glass. 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1983-1. Floral pattern, no image: heart and rectangle. Broken corner. 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1986-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Chipped corner. 1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1988-1. Floral pattern, no image: 2 hearts. Scratched paint. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1988-2. Floral pattern, no image: heart and rectangle. 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1989-1. Floral pattern, no image: heart. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1989-2. Floral pattern with 2 birds, no image: rectangle. Chipped corner. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1990-1. Floral pattern with bird, no image: 2 hearts. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1991-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. Loose clips. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1992-1. Floral pattern, no image: 2 squares. Warped cardboard. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1992-2. Floral pattern with bird, no image: 2 hearts. Chipped corner. 1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1995-1. Floral pattern, no image: 2 hearts. Scratched paint. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Ruiz, Olga: 1995-2. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Alcanta, Candelario: 1982-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Image askew. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Alcanta, Candelario: 1982-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Image askew. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Guttierez, Francisco: 1980-2. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. 1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Guttierez, Gregoria: 1985-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle and heart. Fair condition. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Guttierez, Guadelupe: 1982-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. Clips no longer work. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1982-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Fair condition. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1982-2. Geometric pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1982-3. Architectural pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Loose back and frame. 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1984-1. Geometric pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1984-1. Geometric pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1985-1. Floral pattern, image of Nuestra Señora de la Soledad del Parral: rectangle. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1986-1. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin Mary: oval. Fair condition. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1990-1. Floral pattern, painted-on image of the Virgin of Guadalupe [no commercially printed illustration]. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1992-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Fair condition. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1993-1. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1995-1. Floral pattern, image of El Santo Niño de Atocha: rectangle. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1995-2. Floral pattern, image of San Isidro: rectangle. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1996-1. Geometric pattern, image of San Ignacio de Loyola: rectangle. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1996-2. Geometric pattern, image of Santa Lucia: rectangle. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1996-3. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1996 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1997-1. Abstract/geometric pattern, Nuestra Señora de Altagraria: rectangle. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1997-2. Floral, San Francisco. Rectangle. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Moreno, Catalina: 1979-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. Rusted clips. 1979 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - León Family: 1990-1. Floral pattern with bird, no image: 5 hearts. Fair condition. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - León Family: 1990-2. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - León Family: 1990-3. Floral pattern with 2 birds, no image: 2 rectangles. Fair condition. 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - León Family: 1991-1. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. 1991 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - León Family: 1997-1: Landscape, Vrgin of Guadelupe: rectangle. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - León Family: 1997-2: No pattern, Jesus Malverde: rectangle. 1997 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - León, Anastacio: 1992-1. Floral pattern, image of Juan Diego and his tilma with the image of the Virgin of Guadalupe. The painted pattern runs right up to the edge of the figures represented instead of forming a border around them. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - León, Anastacio: 1992-2. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: outline. Some smeared paint. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - León, Anastacio: 1992-3. Landscape pattern, images of the eagle and serpent emblem and the Virgin of Guadalupe: oval. Fair condition. 1992 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - León, Anastacio: 1993-1. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. Fair condition. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - León, Anastacio: 1993-2. Floral pattern with 2 birds, no image: rectangle. Loose clips. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - León, Anastacio: 1993-3. Floral pattern, no image: 4 hearts. Scratched and slightly smeared paint. 1993 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - León, Anastacio: 1993-4. Floral pattern, image of Nuestra Señora de la Caridad de Cobre: rectangle. Chipped glass. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - León, Anastacio: 1993-5. Landscape pattern, images of the Eagle & Serpent emblem and the Virgin of Guadalupe: outline. Fair condition. 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - León, Anastacio: 1994-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - León, Anastacio: 1994-2. Memorial panel with dove, hearts, and a floral pattern, image of Luis Donaldo Colosio: rectangle. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995-1. Tin work frame, image of the Mano Poderosa [no glass painting]: rectangle. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995-2. Abstract pattern with tin corner pieces, image of San José: rectangle. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995-3. Cactus pattern, images of the Eagle & Serpent emblem, a heart, and the Virgin of Guadalupe: outline. Fair condition. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - León, Anastacio: 1995-4. Memorial panel with dove, hearts, and the Eagle & Serpent emblem, image of Luis Donaldo Colosio: rectangle. 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-1. Abstract pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-2. Tin Work frame, image of The last supper: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-3. Tin Work frame, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-4. Abstract pattern, image of San Martín Caballero: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-5. Tin Work frame, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - León, Anastacio: 1996-6. Abstract pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1996 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - León, Anastacio: 1997-1. Geometric, San Ramon Norrato: rectangle. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - León, Anastacio: 1997-2. Floral, San Francisco: rectangle. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - León, Anastacio: 1997-3. Eagle, serpent, dove and hearts, Virgin of Guadelupe: rectangle. 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - León, Eduardo: 1982-1. Abstract pattern, image of San Alejo: rectangle. Chipped glass and bent frame. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - León, Martín: 1983-1. Floral pattern, no image: 6 hearts. Fair condition. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - León, Martín: 1983-2. Floral pattern, no image: 7 hearts. Chipped corner and scratched paint. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - eón, Martín: 1983-3. Floral pattern, no image: 2 squares. Scratched paint. 1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - León, Martín: 1994-1. Cactus pattern, images of the Eagle & Serpent emblem and the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1994 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - León, Jesús: 1976-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Faded. 1976 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - León, Jesús: 1979-1. Abstract pattern, image of La Omnipresencia de Dios: rectangle. Fair condition. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - León, Jesús: 1979-2. Geometric pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1979 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - León, Jesús: 1980-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Loose Frame. 1980 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - León, Jesús: 1982-1. Floral pattern, image of a guardian angel: rectangle. Broken glass and loose frame. 1982 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - León, Jesús: 1984-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: contains an extra empty panel for purchaser use. Fair condition. 1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - León, Jesús: 1985-1. Floral pattern with birds, no image: 2 rectangles. Scratched paint. 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - León, Jesús: 1985-2. Floral pattern with birds, no image: 2 rectangles. Fair condition. 1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - León, Jesús: 1986-1. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - León, Jesús: 1986-2. Floral pattern, image of Nuestra Señora del Sagrado Corazón: rectangle. Fair condition. 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - León, Jesús: 1987-1. Floral pattern, image of Nuestra Señora del Sagrado Corazón: rectangle. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - León, Jesús: 1987-2. Floral pattern, no image: 3 hearts. Fair condition. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - León, Jesús: 1987-3. Floral pattern, image of San Ramón Nonnatus: rectangle. Fair condition. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - León, Jesús: 1987-4. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Fair condition. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - León, Jesús: 1987-5. Abstract pattern, images of Eagle & Serpent emblem, San Francisco, the vision of the Virgin of Guadalupe, and an Angel: rectangle. Fair condition. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - León, Jesús: 1988-1. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - León, Jesús: 1988-2. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Fair condition. 1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - León, Jesús: 1989-1. Floral pattern, images of the Virgin of Guadalupe and the Eagle & Serpent emblem: oval. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - León, Jesús: 1989-2. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: oval. Fair condition. 1989 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - León, Jesús: 1990-1. Abstract pattern, image of Santa Eduviges: rectangle. 1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Unknown: 1987-1. "Benedice esta casa", image of San Francisco: outline. Plastic frame, Fair condition. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Unknown: 1987-2. Floral pattern, no image: rectangle. 1987 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Unknown: 1991-1. Abstract pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. Octagonal frame, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Unknown: 1991-2. Floral pattern, image of San Francisco: rectangle. 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Guttierez, Francisco: [no date]-1. Floral pattern, image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. Frame loose. No Date (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Unknown: 1991-3. Floral pattern, image of San Martín Caballero: rectangle. Frame, backing, and image are all loose. 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series III: Boxes, 1980-
  Boxes are designated by appending the letter "b" to the date. All pieces labeled "Francisco Silva family" were acquired at the Silva booth, however, the specific artist within the family is unknown. All are in good condition unless otherwise noted.
  - Guttierez, Francisco: 1980b-1. Geometric pattern, image of El Santo Niño de Atocha: rectangle. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - León, Jesús: 1980b-1. Floral pattern. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - León, Jesús: 1981b-1. Floral pattern. 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - León, Jesús: 1989b-1. Abstract and cactus patterns, images of Juan Diego and the Virgin of Guadalupe. 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1982b-1. Floral pattern. 1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1987b-1. Floral and Abstract patterns. 1987 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1994b-1. Floral and geometric patterns. 1994 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1997b-1. Abstract floral patterns. 1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Alcanta, Candelario: 1982b-1. Floral pattern. Broken glass on lid. 1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - León, Matilde: 1996b-1. Clear glass box with decorative tin work, statuette of the Virgin of Guadalupe, and dried flowers. This piece resembles a nicho, or small shrine. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Moreno, Álvaro: 1988b-1. Floral and geometric patterns, 3-D image of the Virgin of Guadalupe: rectangle. This piece resembles a nicho, or small shrine. 1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Francisco Silva family: 1993b-1. Abstract and geometric patterns. 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Unknown: b-1. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Unknown: b-2. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Unknown: b-3. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Unknown: b-4. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Unknown: b-5. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Unknown: b-6. Statuette of San Francisco in a clear glass box. 1980- (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Unfinished Works, Templates, and Comparison Pieces
  Various pieces which illustrate the stages of work in the creation of reverse painted glass. Unfinished pieces show rough outlines of the finished designs, or early stages in the painting process. The series includes several comparison pieces which are mass-produced, or from other cultural traditions. Comparison pieces are identified by the letters "CP" and a numeral, followed by their place of origin or provenance.
  - Unfinished pieces. No Date (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Unfinished pieces. No Date (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Unfinished pieces. No Date (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Hand-drawn template. No Date (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - CP1. Oaxaca, Mexico. No Date (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - CP2. Bavaria, Germany. No Date (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - CP3. Mass-produced piece. No Date (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series V: Photographs, 1965-
  Photographs of Magdalena de Kino painted glass artisans, and San Francisco festival scenery. Also includes general photographs of Sonoran scenery, roadside shrines in Sonora and in the Tohono O'odham nation.
  - Photographs. 1965- (Box 9-11)
- Series VI: Pieces From Other Arizona/Sonora Borderland Locations, 1998-1999
  Boxes, tin cutouts, and other pieces collected from locations in the Arizona/Sonora bordeland other than Magdalena de Kino,Sonora. Many of the same artistsfrom the Magdalena de Kino pieces are represented. Location in which item was procured is indicated after piece number.
  - León, Anastacio: 1998-1. Tumacacori Mission. Tin cutout, image of Tumacacori. Accompanying documentation. 1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - León, Anastacio: 1999-1. Tumacacori Mission. Box with geometric patterns on sides and postcard of Tumacacori Mission under glass lid. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - León, Anastacio: 1999-2. Tumacacori Mission. Rectangular, painted glass image of Blessed Kateri Tekakwitha. 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)